

me@cheukwing.dev | ☆ cheukwing.dev | ☑ cheukwing | ் cheukwing

## Summary \_\_\_\_\_

Final year Imperial College student with a range of experiences in computer science from education, industry, and the wider community - including contributions to open source, teaching to young students, and development of applications from idea to product. Has a particular interest in functional programming and distributed systems.

### Education

#### **Imperial College London**

MENG IN COMPUTING (PREDICTED FIRST CLASS)

Oct 2016 - Jun 2020

- Modules include: 81% Type Systems, 81% Distributed Algorithms, 79% Information and Coding Theory.
- Engineering Dean's List for top 10% performance in second year.
- · Won Morgan Stanley Prize for top 12 first year students.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Jetstack** 

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Apr 2019 - Sep 2019

- Completely rewrote the frontend of Flightdeck (a web application for Kubernetes training) to **Elm** best practices, facilitating and subsequently supporting the onboarding of a new frontend engineer.
- Contributed to Cert-Manager, the open source Kubernetes project for managing TLS certificates, becoming the 5th top contributor at the time.
- · Co-led the design and implementation of Aerodrome, a platform for the provisioning of arbitrary environments to play Flightdeck training scenarios upon, building Kubernetes controllers in Go and making thorough use of Docker and Google Cloud.
- · Participated in bi-weekly sprint planning, sprint retrospectives, and daily stand-ups, gaining industrial experience of Agile development.

Ocado Technology

TECHNOLOGY INTERN

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Connected together several pieces of sensor hardware with several computer vision libraries to develop a single C++ library with which to track the real time movements of a person.
- Developed the library into a Javascript Electron video conferencing application robot-video-conf, using WebRTC to transmit and map the movements to a remote, life-size, robotic upper body.

## Projects \_\_\_\_\_

#### **Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis (ABSA)**

Available on GitHub

THIRD YEAR GROUP PROJECT

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

- · As a group of 6, developed a rule-based NLP solution for the extraction and storage of entity-attribute pairs with their calculated sentiment using **Python**.
- · Showcased the use of the solution for sentiment aggregation in aiding the work of a financial analyst by building a demo application with a **RESTful Python** backend and **React** frontend.

Lembas Available on Request

WEBAPPS GROUP PROJECT

Jun 2018

- In a group of 4, developed a full stack React/Node/PostgreSQL web application for the creation and sharing of balanced meal plans.
- Implemented human-centered-design techniques including user stories and micro-iterations for UX design from demoing and surveying potential users

# Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_\_\_

### Imperial College London (Department of Computing)

PERSONAL PROGRAMMING TUTOR

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019

- · Ran a weekly tutorial with a group of 8 first-year students to supplement their Haskell and Java learning, expanding their knowledge of algorithms and good software design practices.
- Marked and gave feedback to weekly assignments, highlighting mistakes and ways to improve.

**Robogals London** 

TRAINING MANAGER Apr 2017 - Apr 2018

- Regularly volunteered to teach groups of schoolchildren in workshops to program Lego robots, introducing them to the basics of programming.
- Prepared and led training days to on-board new volunteers.
- · Designed new workshops and teaching materials to increase the range of skills taught by the society.